https://www.vinylengine.com/site-policy.shtml

Site Policy
We aim to offer the highest quality service at all times. Listed below are the policies we support.
Privacy
Vinyl Engine respect your right to privacy and we understand that users of our web site need to be in control of their personal information. "Personal information" includes, but is not limited to, name, address, telephone number and e-mail address. Under normal circumstances Vinyl Engine does not sell, rent, swap or otherwise disclose any of this information. See notes*
Use of the Website
Posting constitutes acceptance. Posting messages/images/files on this website constitutes acceptance of these rules and denotes that you agree to adhere to them. Any visitor to the Vinyl Engine website may view content except that within the members area but must register prior to posting to the Vinyl Engine Discussion Forum. When Visitors or Members send email inquiries to Vinyl Engine, the return email address is used to answer the email inquiry we receive. Vinyl Engine does not use the return email address for any other purpose and does not share the return email address with any third party except in cases of abuse. The Vinyl Engine may exercise editorial control over the content of the web site, posting of attachments or other material created or accessible on the Vinyl Engine web site. The Vinyl Engine reserves the right to terminate member accounts at any time without notice. Vinyl Engine may remove any materials that, in our sole discretion, may be illegal, may subject us to liability, or which may violate the Violations of Acceptable Use listed below. Vinyl Engine may cooperate with legal authorities and/or third parties in the investigation of any suspected or alleged crime or civil wrong. By posting messages/images/files, the posting party warrants and represents that he or she owns the copyright with respect to such material or has received permission from the owner. In addition, the posting party grants Vinyl Engine the exclusive right and license to display, copy, publish, distribute, transmit, print and use such information or other material.
Violations of acceptable use
The following constitute violations of acceptable use:
a. Illegal use. Using the Vinyl Engine web site to transmit any material (by email, uploading, posting, or otherwise) that, intentionally or unintentionally, violates any applicable local, state, national or international law, or any rules or regulations promulgated there under.
b. Bad language should be kept to a minimum and any messages containing language likely to offend other visitors may be deleted. Statements relating to sexual orientation, race, religion or other factors having no relevance to the subject may be deleted, as will any posts deemed offensive, inappropriate or libelious.
c. Threats. Using the Services to transmit any material (by email, uploading, posting, or otherwise) that threatens or encourages bodily harm or destruction of property.
d. Harassment. Using the Vinyl Engine web site to transmit any material (by email, uploading, posting, or otherwise) that harasses another. This is to include unwarranted and unsolicited e-mail or private messages from others unless directly associated with Vinyl Engine efforts.
e. Fraudulent activity. Using the Vinyl Engine web site to make fraudulent offers to sell or buy products, items, or services or to advance any type of financial scam or falsely solicit information from others participating in the Vinyl Engine.
f. Cloaking Services. These services are commonly used by spammers, hackers and trolls, or simply to bypass IP restrictions. Repeated use of a cloaking service such as a VPN or Proxy Server may result in your account being deleted without notice.
g. Copyright or trademark infringement. Using the Vinyl Engine web site to transmit any material (by email, uploading, posting, or otherwise) that infringes any copyright, trademark, patent, trade secret, or other proprietary rights of any third party, including, but not limited to, the unauthorized copying of copyrighted material, the digitization and distribution of photographs from magazines, books, or other copyrighted sources, and the unauthorized transmittal of copyrighted software.
h. Collection of personal data. Using the Vinyl Engine web site to collect, or attempt to collect, personal information about third parties without their knowledge or consent.
i. PM abuse. The PM system is subject to the same rules as forum posts eg spam, site moderation, religious or political material etc In addition filters are in place to flag PMs containing spam links or messages to/between previously banned visitors. Abuse of the PM system may result in your account being deleted without notice.
j. Disagreements are acceptable. Debates are acceptable. Flame wars are not. Please do not harass or flame other posters in this forum.
k. Multiple registrations. To prevent abuse of our free service, visitors are allowed one account/user name per person/household/business etc. It is not permitted to register multiple accounts, be it for your partner, dog, workmate etc, or to delete your account then return using a different user name.
l. Adult or illegal content, references or links of an adult nature are not permitted. Posts, threads or links that contain adult or illegal content, nude/topless/pornographic material, or sexual innuendo may be deleted and the member suspended at our discretion.
m. Spamming of website addresses. While external links that are of interest to members are welcome in posts, we reserve the right to remove/edit posts or signatures which are considered by moderators to be website promotions or product advertising. Spamming of the site will also result in a permanent ban on the spammed company/URL - spam this site and you will never get another link/recommendation on this site, regardless of it's relevance or who posts it, it will be removed. Please note that as the Vinyl Engine has no control of the content of external web pages, and to prevent spam, all external links are appended with the 'nofollow' tag and will not improve SEO.
n. Email addresses and telephone numbers. Personal or business email addresses/telephone numbers/contact details should not be included in any forum post/comment page.
o. Links to other forums. Links to forum posts are generally permitted but see notes above regarding spamming. Links/adverts inviting members to join to newly formed forums (eg 'breakaway forums') are not be permitted without prior permission and all such posts will be considered spam.
p. Politics and religion. Discussion of politics and religion are prohibited. Please keep such discussions for a more appropriate venue. Threads, replies or comments containing political or religious comment may be edited/deleted and the member(s) responsible suspended at our discretion.
r. Racist, xenophobic or sexist comment in forum posts or private messages will not tolerated; racist, xenophobic or sexist comments in any form may be deleted without notice and the member suspended at our discretion.
s. Bandwidth Abuse. The use of site copying or offline browsing software is strictly prohibited and will result in permanent removal of access privileges.
t. Forum Post Editing/Deletion. Post editing tools are provided for members to fix spelling and/or formatting errors in forum posts. Any member that uses the editing tools to delete posts after they have been responded to may be given a warning/suspension/ban at the discretion of the forum moderator. Members using the tools to mass edit/delete their old posts will automatically receive a permanent ban.
u. Moderation Decisions. Moderation decisions, site policy, ban lists, spam controls, word censors etc are confidential, at the discretion of the site owner and are not open to discussion in this forum or elsewhere. Posts or personal messages that are critical of the site policy may be edited/deleted and the poster may be given a warning/suspension/ban at the discretion of the forum moderator. The forum has a low level of moderation so we ask members to respect the site policy. If you discuss/criticise moderation decisions and/or site policy elsewhere it will be assumed that you no longer agree with/respect the site policy and your account will be removed and we ask that you use another website in future, thank you.
v. Whining Posts: This website and it's services are provided free if charge. You are not a customer, you are a guest and are expected to behave as such. If you make a public post
here or elsewhere critising this website or it's members it will be considered a resignation of your account and any attempt to register a new account will be treated as abuse and dealt with accordingly.
w. Thread Hijacking. Starting a forum thread does not constitute ownership and during a discussion subject matter may naturally drift off topic over time - if you feel a thread would benefit from being split please contact the webmaster to suggest this - do not attack other posters to the thread.
x. Disruptive Behaviour. Members who make aggressively worded or confrontational posts, who appear to have an agenda against a manufacturer/person website etc, or who are felt to have a disruptive effect on the forum, may be suspended/banned from the site at the moderators discretion.
Special posting rules for trade members
For the purposes of these rules, Trade Members include anyone involved in the Music/HiFi industry eg manufacturers, wholesalers, retailers, commercial partners, affiliates etc, and their friends and family members.
Trade Members are welcome to participate in the forum but only in a private capacity. Self-promotion or advertising in any form is strictly prohibited and the following rules have been devised to preserve the non-commercial nature of the forum.
Forum Posts
Trade Members must not start new threads relating to their business interests, directly or indirectly. They should also avoid any involvement in discussions about products/services in which they have a financial interest. The forum is not intended to be a replacement for official product support and/or a promotional tool.
Trade Members have a limited 'right to reply' where products/services in which they have a financial interest are discussed in the main forum, but they should not intervene in critical evaluations of their products by other members except to correct factual errors. Any such response should be short, to the point and made in a single post. It must not contain any criticism of other members/posts.
Trade Members must not offer a service/product in response to a general query (eg what turntable should I buy?)
Trade Members must not comment on the design/efficacy of services/products provided by other traders where there is a conflict of interest eg sellers of turntable X should not make critical statements about turntable Y where the two products are in competition.
Signatures and Avatars
Trade Members are not permitted to have text, images, videos, addresses, taglines or website links in their posts or signatures as these are considered an advertisement or promotion of a commercial site. All such content will be considered spam and removed.
Links
Trade members must not include links to their websites or address/telephone number etc in any comment, post, signature, personal message etc, or give incentives to any other member to provide such a link.
Interpretation and application of these rules is at the discretion of the forum moderator. All decisions are final.
Deleted/Moved Posts or Closed Threads
Sometimes posts are deleted/moved or threads closed. Certainly posts that break any of the above rules will be deleted or moved, but often posts that are in full compliance with the rules are also deleted. This includes double posts and posts that are perceived by the forum moderators to be in the wrong forum section. The primary reasons are twofold: one, the amount of disk space consumed by the forum is always a concern, so sometimes posts are deleted to conserve space; two, because forum posts are archived for future perusal, posts that are not of enduring and somewhat broad interest may be culled at our discretion. Note, by the way, that message deletions are never personal; it's just the way the system works. If a post of yours gets deleted/moved or a thread closed, don't post about it. Inexplicably, the realization that posts have been deleted/moved or thread closed prompts some to post to the forum asking why. These posts are most definitely not of enduring interest for future perusal by general audiences. Therefore, they will be deleted and the member may be suspended indefinitely from further posting at our discretion. In any case, it does not make sense to post such questions to the forum anyway. The readers of the forum do not delete posts the forum admin does. If a post gets deleted, the best you'll get from anybody else about why is speculation. If you want to ask about why a post was deleted, contact the webmaster rather than posting the question to everybody. Note, however, that most of the time you won't get any more detailed an answer than the explanation in the previous bullet item as usually there isn't more of an explanation than that. In any case deleted posts are irrecoverable.
Private Messaging
The private messaging system is a feature which allows registered members to have uninterrupted conversations outside of the main forum arena. It is not a secure messaging system and shouldn't be used to exchange important information such as bank details etc. Use of the private messaging system to criticise other members, the site moderation or the site in general is not permitted and may result in your account being restricted or closed.
It should also be noted that the administration of the site has full access to the text of such messages and should any member be suspected of being in violation of forum rules their messages may be reviewed as part of any ongoing investigation into their conduct. Messages may be deleted/republished in whole or in part where the moderators of the forum feel it is the general interest. This includes messages from 3rd parties where applicable. The general rule is, do not post anything in a PM that you would not post in the general forum.
Note that use of the PM system for commercial solicitation or sale of goods or services to members is expressly prohibited.
Registration forms
In our registration forms, Vinyl Engine may ask you for personal identifying information, such as your name & e-mail address for internal record-keeping, discount schemes and database purposes. In our registration forms, Vinyl Engine may ask you for contact information, such as your e-mail address or phone number, to communicate with you for daily operational and business reasons, to send you materials or information about Vinyl Engine. Vinyl Engine registration forms are aimed to better our understanding and needs of our web site users, these forms may also request demographic information, such as gender.
Children's Privacy
We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have personal information on a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information from our systems. Please teach children to not give out their names or other personal information to anyone on the Internet. They should also be instructed not to fill out any forms or register at any web site without your knowledge and consent.
Corrections and Updates
From time to time Vinyl Engine will have cause to update or make corrections to the information on the site, Vinyl Engine are not liable for errors. If you our customer see such errors then please contact us immediately identifying the problem.
Links
Our site includes links to other web sites whose privacy policies we don't control. Once you leave our servers (you can check where you are by checking the URL in the location bar on your browser), use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you are visiting. That policy may differ from ours. If you can't find the privacy policy of any of these sites via a link from the site's homepage, you should contact the site directly for more information. Vinyl Engine is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.
The Law
This Site was developed in the United Kingdom in accordance with and shall be governed by, and your browsing in and use of the Site shall be deemed acceptance of, English laws of the United Kingdom. Notwithstanding the foregoing, this Site may be viewed internationally and may contain references to products or services not available in all countries. References to a particular product or service do not imply that Vinyl Engine intends to make such products or services available in all such countries.
Trademarks
All rights reserved. All other trademarks and trade names are properties of their respective owners.
Material
Material may not be copied, reproduced, republished, downloaded, posted, broadcast or transmitted in any way except for your own personal non-commercial home use. Any other use requires the prior written permission from Vinyl Engine. By browsing Vinyl Engine web site you agree not to adapt, alter or create a derivative work from any of the material contained in this site or use it for any other purpose other than for your personal non-commercial use. You agree to use this site only for lawful purposes, and in a manner which does not infringe the rights of, or restrict or inhibit the use and enjoyment of this site by any third party. Such restriction or inhibition includes, without limitation, conduct which is unlawful, or which may harass or cause distress or inconvenience to any person and the transmission of obscene or offensive content or disruption of normal flow of dialogue within this site.
Disclaimer
Vinyl Engine assumes no responsibility, and shall not be liable for any damages to or viruses that may infect, your computer equipment, software, data, or other property on account of you access to, use of, or browsing in the Site or your downloading of any materials, data, text, images, video, or audio from the Site or any linked sites. In no event shall Vinyl Engine or any other party involved in creating, producing, maintaining, or delivering the Site, or any of their affiliates, or the officers, directors, employees, shareholders, or agents of each of them, be liable for any damages of any kind, including without limitation any direct, special, incidental, indirect, exemplary, punitive, or consequential damages, whether or not advised of the possibility of such damages, and on any theory of liability whatsoever, arising out of or in connection with the use of performance of, or your browsing in, or your links to other sites from, this Site.
Collection of Information
Log Files
Like most web sites we use log files which store IP addresses, browser type, ISP, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track userâ€™s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.
Cookies
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the userâ€™s computer tied to information about the user. This site uses cookies for user authentication. If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options.
Advertisers
We use advertising companies to display ads on our site. These adverts may contain cookies and/or web beacons to collect data in the ad serving process and are collected by those companies. Please check the websites of the advertisers for their respective privacy policies.
Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site. Their use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to this sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy
Revisions to This Policy
Vinyl Engine reserves the right to revise, amend, or modify this policy, our Privacy and Security Notice and our other policies and agreements at any time.
Notes
The Vinyl Engine takes spam very seriously. To fight spam and other site/forum posting abuse, reports will be made to the spam abuse department of Internet Service Providers. The privacy policy applies to regular visitors and is null and void should a user register multiple accounts to abuse the service.
Library
Manuals
Upload Scans
Cartridge Protractors
Forum Topics
Acos 81-1 Ceramic Cart Wiring...Rank Domus Turntable?Opinions And Help Deciding On...Cartridge/stylus/phono PreampSeparate System?Struggling To Find A Working...Stanton 680ee Vs Shure V15 IiiPl-570 Tonearm Won’t Dock
Design and Content © Vinyl Engine 2002-2020
HiFi Engine | FAQ | Site Policy | Advertising | Cookie Options
